Once upon a time, once upon a place,
“很久很久以前，在某個地方
there was a monstrous lumberjack.
住著一個怪物樵夫
A monster who pretended to be a lumberjack,
怪物樵夫喬裝成樵夫
and lived among people.
住在人類的村子裡
It hid its big ears and sharp fangs,
他藏起了大大的耳朵和尖尖的牙齒
so no one realized the lumberjack was a monster.
所以沒有人發現他是個怪物”
Can I help you?
有什麼事嗎？
Mr. Kazuo Toma?
你是東間和夫先生吧
We have a court-issued warrant to search your home.
法院已核發搜索府上的令狀
Where is your wife?
你太太在哪裡呢？
Midori! It's the cops! Run!
翠，警察來了，快逃！
"Mr. Lumberjack, Mr. Lumberjack."
“‘樵夫先生…
"Chop some wood for me,"
分一點柴薪給我吧’
"said the old lady baker."
賣麵包的婆婆對他說
"Sure."
‘好啊
"I'll chop wood for you."
我會把柴薪分給你
"So let me into your house, won't you?"
所以，讓我進你家吧’
"Come in, come in."
'請進…
"Please come in any time you like."
隨時歡迎你來‘
"The old lady led the way,
在婆婆的邀請下
and the monstrous lumberjack entered the old lady's house."
怪物樵夫走進了婆婆的家”
Midori Toma?!
你是東間翠吧？
"Then, as soon as it entered,
“接著
it hit her head with its axe."
怪物樵夫就用斧頭朝婆婆的頭揮下”
What did you do to him?
你對那孩子做了什麼？
Oh dear.
哎呀
You're only worried about him?
你只擔心這個孩子嗎？
Where are the other kids?!
其他的孩子們在哪裡？
Where could they be?
在哪裡呢？
"Munch, munch, gulp."
“嚼…
"The monstrous lumberjack
怪物樵夫
ate the old lady."
把婆婆吃掉了”
Kitajima!
北島先生！
The next room…
隔壁的房間…
What about it?
怎麼了？
Children…
發現了孩子們…
The bodies of children…
孩子們的屍體…
-What? -Possibly…
-什麼？ -似乎…
Fifteen bodies…
有15具
Step away from that boy.
離那孩子遠一點
Don't!
住手！
LUMBERJACK THE MONSTER
《怪物樵夫》
You alright?
你還好嗎？
Sugitani's hospital…
杉谷的醫院
General Affairs?
總務部？
Call an ambulance… please…
幫我叫救護車…拜託
Why did you tail me?
你為什麼要跟蹤我？
I found forged death certificates…
我找到了偽造的死亡證明書
Several of them…
而且有好幾份
So…
因為這一點
I realized Sugitani was dumping bodies…
我才發現杉谷擅自處理屍體的事
Why not take it to police first?
這樣的話，一般人會去報警吧？
I thought I could make some money!
我想說可以靠這件事來賺錢
But why did you tail me?
就算如此，你幹嘛要跟蹤我？
You're close with Sugitani…
你跟杉谷很親近
You were on a security camera when certificates were issued.
而且我看到監視攝影機 在證明書開立當天拍到了你
I figured you were involved!
心想你可能和這件事有關
Aha.
這樣啊
That sharp eye of yours proved to be fatal, huh?
原來你是被自己敏銳的直覺害得喪命
"Fatal"?
喪命？
Got a dashcam?
行車記錄器呢？
You should.
你應該要裝的
Road rage is the new normal.
這年頭常有人逼車
Help me…
救救我吧
Please!
拜託
I'm begging you, Mr. Ninomiya!
求求你，二宮先生
Why are you crying?
你在哭什麼？
Are you crazy?!
你瘋了嗎？
You're a lawyer!
你是個律師吧！
Hey… What are you… Hey!
喂，你打算做什麼？喂！
ASSISTANT DIRECTOR
（副院長室）
-Oops. -Sorry!
-抱歉 -對不起
Thank you.
謝謝
Excuse me.
我告辭了
Take care now.
辛苦了
From the Metro Police Analysis Center.
他們是警視廳調查支援分析中心的人
Not because of you, Akira.
他們不是來問你的事啦，彰
Serial murders in Tokyo.
東京都內發生了連續殺人案
They asked if it could be a psychopath.
他們想詢問 凶手是否可能患有精神病疾患
Anyway, what brings you here?
不過，你怎麼會跑來？
That Yabe?
-總務部的矢部？ -是啊
Kind of a gloomy guy.
有點陰沉的傢伙
He was misusing funds. Dad was going to fire him.
矢部被發現挪用公款
He tried to blackmail us, then your name came up.
他想要找我們醫院的把柄
What about me?
為什麼會查到我？
Well,
當然是因為…你解決掉那麼多人 這種事遲早會發生
Your so-called "experiments"
跟你以實驗之名
on live humans are much worse.
對活人做的那些事比起來 根本不算什麼
Medical progress requires it.
這在醫療界是稀鬆平常的
I mean,
話說
I got tired of cats, you know?
我已經厭倦用貓做實驗了
I'll delete the security footage of you. You're safe.
我會刪掉監視攝影機檔案裡
Sugitani.
杉谷
I'm here because I'm not safe.
就是因為有關係，我才會過來
Three days have passed since Saburo Iwata, 36,
36歲的岩田三郎在品川區一間公寓中
was found dead due to head trauma at a Shinagawa apartment,
遭人發現頭部受創身亡後
but no promising new leads have been found.
至今尚未找到有力的線索
Police believe the murder of Taito housewife Masumi Ishikawa,
上週同樣遭人發現 頭部受創身亡的台東區主婦
found dead due to head trauma last week, might be connected…
石川真澄的案件 凶手疑似與本案相同，警方…
What the hell…?
你是什麼人？
Want money?
你的目的是錢嗎？
I'll give you all I have.
要錢的話，我全都給你
Monsters like you…
你們這些怪物
deserve to die.
非死不可
Huh?
什麼？
Help!
來人！快來人啊！
What did I do to you?
我跟你有什麼冤仇？
That freak…
那傢伙…
is gonna fucking die.
我一定要殺了他
Attention!
起立！
Salute!
敬禮！
At ease.
坐下吧
At ease!
坐下！
In response to the two head trauma murders,
繼上野之後 品川也發現了頭部受創身亡的遺體
we've set up an investigation team.
我們已設置特別調查總部 正在努力調查中
It seems they were committed by the same perp,
根據目前為止的調查成果
so we'll treat them as serial killings.
調查將朝連續殺人案的方向進行
Unit Chief Hirose, share your intel.
廣瀨組長
The media are unaware
這部分沒有對媒體公開
"head trauma" is an understatement.
頭部受創是比較溫和的形容
Both victims were hit repeatedly with an axe-like weapon,
兩位被害人的頭部
and had their brains removed.
腦部全被挖除
The first victim. Masumi Ishikawa, 39, female.
第一起案件的被害人石川真澄
A housewife and former hostess,
原本是公關小姐，現為專職主婦的她
whose pyramid schemes ruined many lives.
卻從事多層次傳銷
Even her neighbors speak ill of her.
根據訪查 她在鄰居口中的名聲也相當差
The latest victim is Saburo Iwata.
這次的被害人為岩田三郎
36, male, unemployed.
36歲男性，失業中
Four convictions. Injury, rape…
有傷害和強姦等四項前科
Hated by many.
許多人對他懷恨在心
We're checking alibis, but there are no suspects as yet.
正在確認所有相關人士的不在場證明 但目前尚未發現可疑人物
No signs of struggle at either scene.
兩起案發現場都沒有打鬥的跡象
The perp waited in their homes, and attacked from behind.
犯人可能是埋伏在屋內，從後方偷襲
No valuables were taken.
兩起案件都沒有貴重物品被帶走
The perp's most likely the same person,
從手法看來，很可能是同一個凶手
but the victims were unconnected.
兩位被害人之間完全沒有共通點
SSBC Analyst and Inspector Toshiro.
調查支援分析中心 情報分析組的戶城警部
Is it possible we have a lust killer?
請問追求殺戮本身的 淫樂殺人可能性有多高？
I'd say that's unlikely.
我認為可能性很低
Lust killers tend
淫樂殺人通常涉及性衝動
but Ishikawa and Iwata share no similarities.
石川和岩田則不只性別 外型也截然不同
The MO seems impulsive, but it was systematic.
此外，雖然乍看是衝動行事 犯人的行為卻井然有序
A route was plotted beforehand
為了從監視攝影機拍不到的路線入侵
to avoid security cameras.
必須事前進行調查
Ambushes require patience, and no evidence was left.
並且採用了埋伏這種需要耐心的手段
Which suggests,
從這一點看來
the perp had a specific motive for killing these two.
犯人應該有 非殺這兩人不可的明確動機
A clear sign of psychopathic tendencies.
犯人無疑具有心理病態的傾向
The victims must be connected somehow.
被害人之間 一定有著不為人知的共通點
We need to figure that out.
首先應該要調查這一點
Unless we catch the killer,
只要沒被我們抓到
these killings won't ever stop.
這個凶手絕對不會停止犯案
Tell me about this brain thief.
關於這個偷腦賊，你還知道些什麼？
"Brain thief"?
偷腦賊？
If you say so.
要這麼說也可以啦
Methodical, yet has the brute strength to swing an axe.
犯人不只井然有序
Probably,
很可能是有出社會工作過
Killing at different times
從行凶時間不一的這點看來
suggests a flexible work schedule,
犯人可能從事時間較有彈性的工作
or unemployment.
或是無業之人
Inui.
乾
Look into this profiler's notion of an unseen connection.
去查查這位側寫師所說的
"Brain thief" might be good for the media,
偷腦賊或許是個適合媒體報導的稱呼
but it trivializes this case.
但我認為淡化了本案的嚴重性
You sure?
是嗎？
If it wasn't lust or a grudge, it was theft.
如果動機不是快感或冤仇 那就是偷東西吧？
All good I'd say.
看起來沒有問題
Mr. Ninomiya,
就二宮先生的狀況而言
a possible epidural hematoma was a concern,
要擔心的是硬腦膜下血腫
but six hours have passed safely, so you should be fine.
然而最初的六小時危險期已經過去
Heavy intracerebral bleeding worsens hematomas.
腦內的出血量越多，血腫就會越大
It could've been more serious.
這樣的話情況就嚴重了
I'm not in pain,
雖然不覺得痛
but I feel strange.
但好像哪裡怪怪的
Is that so?
是嗎？
At any rate, stay with us for a few days.
總之住院個幾天，觀察一下狀況吧
I have urgent business,
我手上有幾個急件要辦
so I can't…
可能沒辦法住院
Then again, in your case,
話雖如此，就二宮先生的狀況而言
besides your head trauma,
除了外傷之外
I'm concerned about your neuro chip.
我也擔心會不會影響到腦內晶片
It's fragile, and has been in there a while.
畢竟晶片容易壞，又過了這麼久
I recommend a thorough checkup.
還是做個精密檢查比較好
"Neuro chip"?
腦內晶片？
Yes.
是啊
As you know,
眾所皆知，目前這麼做違反倫理規範
When you're discharged, visit a specialist hospital.
請你出院後去專門的醫院進行檢查
What is…
你說的…
a neuro chip?
腦內晶片是什麼？
This is it.
就是這個
This vague pale shadow here.
畫面中這個淡淡的白色物體
You mean…
你該不會…
you didn't know that
不知道吧？
you have a neuro chip in your brain?
自己的腦中被植入了晶片
Oh.
喔
That.
你是說那個啊
That's what you were on about.
那個就是腦內晶片嗎？
There are many names for it.
畢竟有很多種稱呼的方式嘛
I'll contact my usual hospital.
我會馬上跟常去的醫院聯絡
-Please do. -Sure.
-請務必這麼做 -好的
Alright then.
那麼，告辭了
If you feel pain, let us know.
痛起來的話別忍耐，請馬上呼叫我們
I will.
好的
Thank you.
謝謝
QUADRIPLEGIC MAN REHABILITATED BY NEURO CHIP
（四肢癱瘓的男性 因植入腦內晶片而康復）
Why do I have one…?
為什麼這種東西會…
Hey, you don't look so bad.
什麼嘛，你看起來很有精神啊
Emi, you came.
映美小姐，你來看我啊？
You're fine.
每次都這樣，真是白擔心你了
You worried about me?
你有擔心我嗎？
Any pain?
會不會痛？
No, fortunately.
不會，托你的福
Oh.
這樣啊
This is a good time then.
我想趁這個機會告訴你
Don't force yourself to be with me.
你不用再勉強跟我交往了
My dad wanted us to be together so much,
反正那麼希望我們在一起的父親
but he's gone now.
也已經過世了
Don't be silly, Emi.
你在說什麼啊，映美小姐
My feelings for you won't ever change.
我對你的心意從來都沒變喔
Yeah? Glad to hear it.
是嗎？
Mr. Ninomiya, the police are here.
二宮先生，警方的人來了
I'd better go.
那我回去囉
I'm on a break from rehearsals.
我是趁舞台劇排練的空檔偷跑過來的
I know you're busy. Thank you.
百忙中還跑來
It's okay.
不會
Victim 1.
第一起案子的被害人
Masumi Ishikawa, 39, female.
石川真澄，39歲女性
Former hostess. Housewife at the time of death.
原為公關小姐，遇害時為專職主婦
Her pyramid schemes ruined many lives.
從事多層次傳銷的她 手下有許多人受害
The perp was waiting in her home,
犯人可能是埋伏在屋內
and attacked her from behind.
從後方偷襲
No signs of struggle.
沒有打鬥的跡象
Hit repeatedly with an axe-like weapon,
遭到類似斧頭的凶器多次砍殺
and had her brain…
腦部全被…
removed.
挖除
Toshiro, what's your take?
戶城，你怎麼看？
A third victim will be on you.
超過三人受害，就是你的責任
In Behavioral Science at the academy,
學院的行為科學課上教過
we were taught that if a serial killer murders three times,
連續殺人案如果出現超過三位犧牲者
the police are also to blame.
那麼警察也是共犯
That's harsh.
真嚴厲啊
You were right. There's a connection.
還真的被你說中了呢，找到共通點了
Both victims grew up at an orphanage.
他們兩人都是在育幼院長大的
An orphanage?
育幼院？
The thing is, they were different orphanages.
不過問題在於，他們待的育幼院不同
If it were the same, it could be bullying revenge,
如果是同一間的話
or some other simple motive.
能想到這類容易理解的動機
Ishikawa's was in Adachi,
不過，石川待的是足立區
and Iwata's was in Tachikawa.
岩田待的則是立川的育幼院
They were both dumped outside orphanages.
兩人都是被丟在育幼院前的棄兒
This just got more complicated.
這下感覺更加棘手了
That detective…
那位刑警是？
What?
怎麼了嗎？
Can't tell if he's dumb or smart.
搞不懂他是笨還是聰明
Assistant Inspector Inui.
他是本署的乾警部補，是優秀的人才
For a cop,
身為警察的他
his sense of justice is too strong.
正義感卻太強，這點倒是個問題
Just kidding.
開玩笑的
He was elite,
他待在搜查一課的時候
but caused trouble and got shunted to Shinagawa.
引起了與某起事件有關的糾紛
Trouble?
事件？
That insurance murder two years ago.
兩年前涉及保險金的死亡事件
A housewife fell down stairs and died.
一位主婦從自家樓梯墜落身亡
Her husband cried for the cameras,
她的丈夫在電視鏡頭前嚎啕大哭
but got a 50 million insurance payout.
其實卻拿到了五千萬日圓的保險金
Well, he was most certainly guilty.
可以說，他幾乎肯定有罪
But there was no evidence or witnesses, so Kenmochi got off.
然而，由於缺乏物證和證人
Then…
但是…
Hey, don't go. Come on!
聽著，不用花多少時間，喂
At least, apologize at Saki's grave.
至少到咲的墓前謝罪吧
Before I die!
在我死去之前
It was only 50 mil, so quit your damn whining.
不過才五千萬而已，囉哩囉嗦吵死了
You should say sorry for her dying suspiciously.
你反倒該說 “她死得那麼可疑，真是對不起”
You're her father. Apologize.
身為父親的你要替她道歉才對
Give me a break. Apologize.
幹什麼？
Apologize, dammit.
快道歉啊你
What the fuck?
搞什麼鬼啊你？
Inui kept investigating on his own,
-獨自鍥而不捨進行調查的乾 -你想幹嘛？
and they crossed paths.
剛好目睹這一切
Kenmochi's a lowlife,
劍持就是這種無賴
so he sued the police for injury.
他以身體不適為由，向警方提出抗議
Inui couldn't avoid a demotion.
乾不得不遭到貶職
That Kenmochi guy
那個叫做劍持的男人
sounds like a typical psychopath.
具有典型的心理病態特徵呢
A neuro chip, huh…
腦內晶片啊
Yours is an old model.
這是舊型的呢
What's it doing in my head?
這個晶片在我的腦子裡做什麼？
Lately,
最近又開始有人在開發 運用AI的腦內晶片呢
In the beginning,
腦內晶片起初
they were created to stimulate paralyzed limbs.
是為了幫助四肢癱瘓的患者重新行動
As the technology advanced,
隨著技術發展
they were also used to suppress emotions.
也開始被用來控制情感
But before long,
但不久後
criminals and others seen as mentally disturbed
有些罪犯和心理有問題的人
were operated on without consent.
在未經同意的情況下被動了手術
Neuro chips were described as modern-day lobotomies.
腦內晶片被視為 “現代的腦白質切除術”
About 30 years ago,
於是在30年前左右
their use was banned worldwide.
遭到全世界禁用
When were you left at that orphanage?
你是什麼時候被丟在育幼院前的？
About that long ago.
差不多是在那時候
Then, you were operated on before that.
這樣的話
In your case, this…
你的狀況，晶片的位置在這
This is your brain's morality and empathy center.
這裡是
Morality and empathy…
道德和同理心…
Why implant a neuro chip there?
為什麼要在那種地方植入腦內晶片？
Maybe, to suppress abnormal behavior,
或許是有人想抑制你的異常行為
your orbital cortex and amygdala activity
利用腦內晶片來刺激 眼窩額葉皮質和杏仁核周圍的活動
Knowing the procedure was illegal.
在明知這種手術違法的情況下
Did they honestly think I'd change?
他們以為這樣就能改變我嗎？
Your parents asked for it,
你爸媽委託進行手術後
but no change made them dump you.
發現沒有變化，就把你丟到育幼院
That's just a guess.
應該是這樣吧
Excluding our kind, the world's full of idiots.
畢竟世界上充滿了與我們不同的笨蛋
We psychopaths are the chosen ones.
我們心理病態者是天選之人
We follow no one.
我們不在乎他人的想法
We don't fear risk. We make history.
也不害怕風險，才使歷史大幅演進
History views Oda Nobunaga and Peter the Great as heroes.
織田信長和彼得大帝
Medical research would thrive without pathetic ethics.
若不是平庸之人設下的倫理規範 醫療研究早就更加進步了
Like the stem cell ban…
-能用胚胎幹細胞或受精卵來… -是他
The masked man who attacked me.
攻擊我的就是這個戴面具的傢伙
"Lumberjack the Monster"?
《怪物樵夫》啊
MUNCH, MUNCH, GULP.
（嚼…吞下）
"Lumberjack the Monster."
《怪物樵夫》
Some movie based on a picture book, apparently.
好像是繪本改編的電影
Where next?
你要去哪裡？
I've got to beat the police…
我得比警察早一步
to finding that masked monster.
找到那個戴面具的怪物
Why?
為什麼？
He said,
他跟我說
"Monsters like you deserve to die."
“你們這些怪物非死不可”
He knows what I've done.
他知道我做過什麼事
Who knows what he'll tell the cops.
天曉得被警察抓到的話他會說些什麼
"Monsters like you"?
“你們這些怪物”？
Such as me?
包括我在內嗎？
Maybe.
說不定喔
But you don't look like one.
你看起來不太像怪物就是了
LUMBERJACK THE MONSTER
（《怪物樵夫》）
"Munch, munch, gulp."
“嚼…吞下
"The monstrous lumberjack
怪物樵夫
ate Helena the florist next."
接著吃了賣花的海倫娜
"However, no one noticed."
然而，完全沒人發現這件事
"Munch, munch, gulp."
嚼…吞下
"The monstrous lumberjack
怪物樵夫
ate Thomas the blacksmith next."
接著吃了鐵匠湯瑪斯
"However, no one noticed."
然而，完全沒人發現這件事
"The lumberjack-mimicking monster
偽裝成樵夫的怪物樵夫
could eat as many people as it liked."
隨時都可以盡情吃人
"And so, the monstrous lumberjack
因此怪物樵夫
lived very happily in the village."
對於住在村莊的生活非常滿意”
You slumming it, Miss Profiler?
側寫師也要來案發現場嗎？
Excuse me.
抱歉借過
The latest victim is Yoshio Mitsuta.
這次的被害人是滿田義男
A freelance photographer.
是自由接案的攝影師
Coroner says he died over four days ago.
根據驗屍官的看法，死亡已超過四天
Like the others, his brain's been removed.
如同前幾起案子，大腦也被拿走了
He was famous for invading people's privacy.
他以用強硬手段拍攝狗仔照出名
Had mob links too.
也跟黑道相關人士有所往來
Maintained a bad rep in his industry.
在業界似乎惡評不斷
Grew up in Sagamihara, at an orphanage.
是在相模原的育幼院長大的
Another orphanage…
果然也是育幼院出身
That's not the only connection.
除此之外，還有其他的共通點
They were all pariahs.
被害人都是過街老鼠
Thankfully, I've been discharged.
托你的福，我已經出院了
So Emi, about your father's law firm.
另外，映美小姐
Before Mr. Hasumi passed away,
荷見律師的遺願
he said I should take over, and our advisors and partners agree,
是希望我來繼承
but what do you think?
但你是怎麼想的？
Why not?
很好啊
You always wanted to be a senior partner at Hasumi Law.
成為荷見法律事務所的資深合夥人
Emi.
映美小姐
If you're against it,
如果你反對的話
I'll turn them down.
我就回絕他們
I…
我…
can't get over my father's death.
至今還無法接受父親的死
He wouldn't kill himself.
是絕對不可能自殺的
You take care of his firm.
事務所就交給你了
I want to retain the name Hasumi Law Office.
我打算保留荷見法律事務所的名稱
I'll be in touch.
那麼，我們再聯絡
Move it. Quit lagging behind.
快一點啦，別在那邊拖拖拉拉
Move your ass.
叫你快一點啦
Hey.
喂…
Hey, shut the hell up.
喂，給我閉嘴喔
Quit crying.
別哭了
Hey. Quit crying already.
喂，別哭了啦，真是的
Hey.
喂
Quit crying, dammit.
不是叫你別哭了嗎？
Quit crying.
你…不准再哭了
Akira, run!
彰，快逃！
Run!
快逃！
What?!
怎樣？
What the fuck?!
搞什麼啊
Show me your face.
把臉露出來
Who the hell…
你…
are you?
到底是誰？
The victim is Mitsuhiko Kobayashi, 37.
被害人是小林光彥，37歲
Bank liaison.
銀行的貸款業務員
Widely hated for harsh credit retraction.
因強行收回貸款的做法而招致怨恨
Same MO.
犯人行凶手法相同
He grew up
果然…
in an orphanage too.
他也是出身自育幼院
Killing out in the open now.
凶手終於在戶外犯案了嗎？
Taking the risk of being seen, killing outside,
甘願冒著可能遭人目擊的風險
Why do you think?
你認為是為什麼？
The perp…
犯人…
is rushing.
著急了
At first, there were a few days between hits,
一開始的三人都是間隔數日遇害
but this was after a 10-day gap.
這次行凶則和上次隔了將近十天
The perp wants every target dead.
犯人想把目標對象全部殺光
But,
然而…
for some reason, time is running out.
卻因為某種理由 使達成目標的時間所剩不多
Perhaps Kobayashi was killed recklessly…
只好冒著風險，強行殺害小林…
due to a prior failed kill?
犯人在某個地方犯下了錯誤
Two weeks ago, in a parking garage,
兩週前在港區一間公寓的停車場
a lawyer sustained a head injury in an attack.
發生了一名30幾歲的律師 遭搶匪襲擊而頭部受傷的事件
A skull fracture, requiring 25 stitches.
被害人頭骨骨折，縫了25針
He's out now though.
但已經出院了
That man…
這個男人是…
This victim had money stolen.
犯人竊走了這位被害人錢包裡的現金
Weapon unknown.
凶器也不明
If it was a mugging, it's unrelated.
如果是以搶劫為目的 就跟本案不符了吧
Hey, Toshiro!
喂，戶城！
Don't go alone!
你別獨自跑去啊
Inui, babysit her.
乾，去當她的保姆
Emi?
映美小姐？
I thought you could use some food…
你才剛出院，生活上可能有些不方便
Okay, I'd better go.
那麼，我走囉
If you'd like, want to come over?
願意的話，要不要上來坐坐？
Come in.
請進
Your hand…
你的手怎麼了？
I fell while jogging.
慢跑的時候跌倒了
I didn't want you to think I'm clumsy.
真不想讓你看到這副糗樣
Don't be silly.
別說傻話
Your bandage is undone. Show me.
你的繃帶鬆開了，讓我看看
You don't have to hide your weaknesses from me.
你不需要對我
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
We met at Dr. Sugitani's hospital.
我們在杉谷醫師那裡見過面吧？
We did. How do you know him?
是啊
He gave medical advice for a case of mine.
以前我曾因為打官司 向他請教過醫學上的建議
What can I do for you?
請問找我有什麼事？
I told the detective in charge all I remember.
我記得的都已經跟轄區的刑警說了
I've read the report.
我讀了警方的報告
I'd like to ask you some further questions.
其中有些地方，我想再確認一下
If you say so, I'm happy to help.
這樣的話
Thank you.
謝謝
First of all,
那麼，首先
do you think you might have brought this on?
二宮先生，你記得自己 曾做過什麼招人怨恨的事嗎？
Hey. Aren't you being rude?
等等，太失禮了吧？
He's a victim of a mugging.
他可是搶劫案的被害人呢
Excuse me, who is she?
抱歉，請問這位是？
My fiancée.
她是我的未婚妻
If you're not his wife, please leave us.
既然你不是他的妻子 可以請你暫時離開一下嗎？
This is a crucial investigation.
我們正在調查一起重大刑案
I'm sorry.
抱歉
You're just doing your job.
刑警小姐也是公事公辦嘛
Akira, take care of yourself.
那麼，彰先生
Thank you.
謝謝
Perhaps she's jealous of your beauty.
可能刑警小姐是個美女
Please forgive her.
還請多多包涵
I've done nothing to incite an attack.
我不記得
I said that last time too.
筆錄中應該也有寫到這點
Mr. Ninomiya.
二宮先生
Was your assailant's weapon an axe?
犯人使用的凶器不是斧頭嗎？
An axe?
斧頭？
I was attacked from behind,
我是從背後遭到攻擊的
so I didn't see.
所以沒有看到
It could've been an axe?
那麼，有可能是斧頭囉？
Leading questions?
這是誘導訊問嗎？
Why are you so determined to make it an axe?
你為什麼這麼希望凶器是斧頭？
Know any of these people?
這裡頭有你認識的人嗎？
Is one of them the mugger who attacked me?
襲擊我的搶匪在這裡頭嗎？
Please answer the question.
請回答我的問題
Aren't these people…?
這些人…
There's that "brain thief." The serial killer who takes brains.
聽說有個“偷腦賊”
These are the victims, aren't they?
他們是被殺害的死者吧？
Talk of a serial killer is media speculation.
連續殺人案的說法只是媒體的推斷
I don't know any of them.
裡頭沒有我認識的人
If they're case witnesses, or clients' relatives,
不過，法庭上的證人或客戶的親戚
I wouldn't remember them all.
我也不是每一個都記得
I see.
這樣啊
For clarity's sake,
我想確認一件事
you grew up in an orphanage, no?
二宮先生你是在育幼院長大的吧？
Why…
你問這個問題
are you asking me that?
是為了什麼呢？
Well,
沒什麼
you rose from hardship to succeed as a lawyer.
你出身低微，卻成為律師出人頭地
That's very admirable.
實在令人敬佩
Is that…
這一點…
relevant to this case?
和案子之間有什麼關係嗎？
We're not ruling it out.
這點也在我們調查的範圍內
If you're truly willing to cooperate,
如果二宮先生是真心願意提供協助
I can share more information.
我可以再多透露一些
Nice effort, fake glasses and all.
你很努力，甚至戴上假眼鏡
But with that attitude,
但用這種態度對待律師
forget about getting promoted.
在警察體系裡是爬不高的喔
You there.
你…
Say something.
都不說句話嗎？
Sorry, but she actually outranks me.
抱歉，但她的官階比我高
Question time's over now.
要問的都有問到，該回去了
Toshiro, let's go.
戶城，我們走吧
Anyway, please take care.
總之，請多加注意安全
Even if it was a mugging,
就算上次真的是遇到搶匪
your assailant might try again.
還是可能再次對你下手
I know who attacked me.
我知道那傢伙的真面目了
That serial killer. The brain thief.
是犯下連續殺人案的偷腦賊
Other victims grew up in orphanages, like me.
被害人似乎跟我一樣都是育幼院出身
The killer's after…
他的目標恐怕是
the neuro chips.
腦內晶片
Disable a security camera to strip a wallet?
只為了搶人家身上的現金 有必要切斷監視攝影機嗎？
A little overcautious for a mugger.
就搶劫而言確實太費周章
That slick lawyer knows more than he's letting on.
那個帥哥律師 為什麼要隱瞞犯人和當時的狀況？
Let's visit his doctor.
去問問為他診斷傷勢的醫生吧
-He's absent? -Yes.
-無故曠職？ -是的
He has appointments, but he's unreachable.
有約好要看診，卻聯絡不上他
Have you told anyone about my neuro chip?
我腦內有晶片的事，你有告訴誰嗎？
No one at all!
我沒跟任何人說過
What'll you do to me?!
你們打算對我做什麼？
If he hasn't talked,
如果他沒說出去的話
don't worry about your CT scan.
就不用擔心電腦斷層影像的事了
Oh.
對了
I'm all for killing him too.
我也贊成殺了他
Killing me?!
殺了我？
Are you two insane?!
你們在說什麼鬼話？
After all,
況且
why's your chip a problem?
腦內晶片有什麼問題嗎？
No idea.
天曉得
Ask the guy who attacked me.
去問那個想殺我的人吧
This is bullshit!
開什麼玩笑！
My phone's GPS will show I'm here.
透過手機的GPS可以查到我在這裡
If you kill me, you're both finished!
要是真的殺了我，你們兩個也會完蛋
Nice try.
想得美
Problem is,
不過
this is your phone.
你的手機，現在是這個樣子
This isn't my first time.
我不是第一次做這種事了
You owe me!
我救了你耶
I saved your life!
我可是你的救命恩人
Why stop?
怎麼了？
Strange…
奇怪
I feel ill.
我覺得很不舒服
So you should!
活該
You tried to kill me.
誰叫你想要殺我
Could be intracerebral bleeding.
說不定是腦出血的影響
Let me take a look!
讓我幫你診斷看看吧
I'm a specialist.
我是這方面的專家
Take him to hospital…
快送他去醫院…
Smartphones really are bad for your health.
說手機對身體不好，還真的呢
I'd like to see a patient's records.
我想查看一位病患的病歷
I'm sorry, I don't have the authority…
對不起，我沒有這個權限
I see.
這樣啊
Sorry to bother you.
抱歉給你添麻煩了
Oh no!
糟糕
Please, don't touch that! I'll clean it up.
那個…請不要碰到
NINOMIYA
（姓名：二宮）
AKIRA
（彰）
-Hey… -As a suspect-beating outcast.
-喂 -我可不想聽一個
You should shut your mouth.
揍了嫌犯而被貶職的人說教
I didn't say anything.
我明明什麼也沒說
SHOW RECORDS
（顯示病歷）
SHOW CT
（顯示斷層影像）
Excuse me…
不好意思
A fracture of the right temporal region.
這是右邊顳部的頭骨骨折
No hematomas, apparently.
看來沒有血腫
A blow from a blunt instrument.
應該是被鈍器之類的東西毆打造成
Not an axe?
不是斧頭嗎？
An axe's butt is blunt enough.
被斧背毆打的話也算是鈍器
Can't say for sure though.
當然是無法斷定啦
The butt…
用斧背…
What's really intriguing is this neuro chip.
真正耐人尋味的是這個腦內晶片
Neuro chip?
腦內晶片？
Banned a long time ago though.
很久以前就已經被禁止使用了
How old is he?
這位患者幾歲？
Thirty-five.
35歲
Thirty-five…
35歲啊
Clearly a non-voluntary illegal procedure.
那麼，很顯然是 沒有經過本人同意的違法手術
Is he doing alright?
這位患者還好嗎？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Neuro chips are fragile.
腦內晶片是很容易損壞的
If the blow fractured his skull,
既然毆打的力道大到能讓頭骨骨折
who knows what else it did?
晶片出了什麼問題也不奇怪
If neuro chips are the target,
如果凶手的目標是腦內晶片
it all makes sense.
一切就合理了
The brains were torn out to get to the chips,
目標是腦內晶片 想必得粗暴地挖出大腦
and smashing skulls would hide signs of craniotomies.
破壞頭蓋骨 也是為了掩蓋開顱手術的痕跡
Hirose,
廣瀨先生
get X-rays of the victims' brains before death.
請去取得被害人生前的腦部X光片
Even just one or two.
只有一、兩個人的也好
Perhaps…
該不會…
at long last,
一直到現在
my neuro chip is starting to work.
我的腦內晶片才開始發揮作用吧？
Maybe the opposite.
一定剛好相反
The opposite?
相反
I found something fascinating.
在那之後，我做了一些調查
A suppressed incident that's legendary in neurosurgery circles.
找到一起沒有對外公開
Toshiro.
戶城小姐
Victim 1 was in a car accident three years ago.
第一起凶案的被害人石川真澄
I got her X-ray.
當時有拍過X光片
Surprisingly, she had a neuro chip,
令人吃驚的是…
and it seems she knew nothing about it.
而且本人似乎並不知情
A neuro chip…
腦內晶片…
So presumably,
這麼一來
not just victim 1,
恐怕不是只有石川
but all the victims had neuro chips.
所有被害人可能都被植入了腦內晶片
How did you find out?
戶城，你怎麼知道這一點？
I'm a profiler.
因為我是側寫師
Right.
也對
So, when did victim 1 receive the chip?
那麼，石川是什麼時候被動手術的？
The orphanage says
根據向院方求證的結果
she had an operation scar when she came.
她進育幼院時就已經有手術的疤痕了
Counting back from then,
從石川進育幼院那天倒推起來
it would've been over 31 years ago.
已經是超過31年以前的事了
Thirty-one years ago…
31年前
children operated on illegally were left at orphanages.
有人把動過違法手術的孩子們
In all likelihood,
也就是說
if we look into prior abduction cases…
只要調查那段期間發生的誘拐事件…
The Shizuoka serial child abductions.
靜岡連續誘拐殺害兒童事件
That's got to be it.
那段期間，就只有這起案子了
AKA, the Toma case.
人稱“東間事件”
The Toma case?
“東間事件”？
Most likely,
彰你可能是
you're an unknown survivor of that incident.
東間事件中不為人知的生還者吧
This is Kitajima. He led the Shizuoka Police investigation.
這位是當時任職靜岡縣警署
He's retired now. Works in traffic safety.
他現在已經退休
I'm Kitajima.
我是北島
This way, sir.
這邊請
Long time no see, Inui.
好久不見了呢，乾先生
It started with one missing child.
最初只是一起失蹤事件
When a couple returned to their car after shopping…
一對夫妻去超市買完東西後回到車上
their son Takeshi
原本應該在車上讀書
wasn't waiting in their car. He was gone.
等待父母回來的小武
Abduction wasn't ruled out,
雖然我們也懷疑可能是被誘拐
but without a ransom demand, we couldn't take action.
但沒人要求贖金，因此也無從調查起
After that,
在那之後
children started going missing in the greater Tokyo area.
關東圈內陸續有幼兒失蹤
Eventually,
終於，有人現場目擊到幼兒被帶走
and it became a serial abduction case.
失蹤案成了連續誘拐兒童事件
Based on the witness report,
我們藉由當時的目擊情報
we found the vehicle that was used,
查出了犯罪時使用的車輛
and the owner.
確信那輛車的車主
Kazuo Toma.
東間和夫
We were sure he and his wife Midori were guilty.
與其妻東間翠應該就是犯人
We got a search warrant,
我們拿著搜索票
and headed for their home in Shizuoka.
前往位於靜岡的東間宅邸
We stormed the place, and what we saw inside…
攻進屋內
was hell on earth.
看見了人間煉獄
Midori Toma
東間翠
opened up the heads of the abducted children,
切開了誘拐來的孩子們的頭骨
and experimented on them with neuro chips.
在頭部植入腦內晶片，進行實驗
Inside their mansion,
我們在宅邸中
we found 15 children who'd died from the surgery,
找到承受不了手術而身亡的15名幼兒
and one child who survived.
以及一位生還者
The first child they abducted, Takeshi.
存活下來的是最初被誘拐的小武
Kazuo testified in court that
東間和夫也在法庭上作證
Takeshi, the oldest abductee, was their only successful test subject.
表示只有年紀最大的小武撐過手術
To protect Takeshi's privacy,
為了維護小武的人權
the neuro chip matter was kept secret.
我們沒對外公開腦內晶片的事
However, Takeshi wasn't the only one.
然而…
There were others,
還有好幾個這樣的孩子四散在各處
What on earth were the Tomas trying to do?
東間夫婦究竟為什麼要做這種實驗？
Trying to turn children into psychopaths.
為了把孩子們改造成心理病態者
You're saying they created psychopaths?
你的意思是 他們製造出了心理病態者？
The Tomas' son was a psychopath.
東間夫婦的兒子就是個心理病態者
He left animals dead and dismembered,
他會將動物分屍，丟棄在路邊
treated docile friends like slaves,
或把懦弱的朋友當成奴隸
and fractured their bones repeatedly.
多次害他們在同一個部位骨折
The neuro chip was developed to cure him.
腦內晶片就是為了治療這一點而開發
Kazuo Toma said so in his testimony.
這是東間和夫在法庭上的證詞
Why not develop surgery to cure psychopathy?
為什麼他們不直接 動手術治療心理病態？
They couldn't find enough
要找到好幾個心理病態者來做實驗 根本是不可能的吧
If you can break it,
知道怎麼弄壞的話
you can unbreak it, huh?
就能搞懂怎麼修復了嗎？
So, they tampered with my brain,
所以他們才亂搞我的大腦
to find a way to cure psychopathy…
希望能找出治療心理病態的方法嗎？
Revenge is impossible.
報仇是不可能的喔
Midori Toma killed herself upon arrest.
東間翠在被捕的當下自殺
Kazuo has already died in prison.
先生和夫也已經死在獄中
Their son died at the age of ten.
就連他們的兒子 也在10歲的時候死了
They could break other kids. Couldn't fix their son.
即使知道怎麼弄壞 他們卻還是搞不懂怎麼修復呢
What'll become of me now?
再這樣下去，我會怎麼樣？
If your neuro chip's broken…
如果腦內晶片損壞
and you leave it,
放著不管的話
maybe it'll make you normal?
你應該就會變回一般人吧
You'll suddenly get an urge to adopt a puppy.
突然想養小狗之類的
Can the chip be repaired?
有辦法修好嗎？
You'd need another one, and your old data.
會需要新的腦內晶片和手術時的資料
It's your most delicate area, so caution is imperative.
植入的地方是最脆弱的腦部
I'll have to catch the masked monster.
既然如此 我就必須逮住那個戴面具的怪物
If he has a list, he'll have my data.
他手上有名單
You don't…
你不打算就這樣…
want to be normal again?
變回一般人嗎？
If I were…
變回一般人
would that be a good thing?
有什麼好處嗎？
How the heck would I know?
我哪知道啊？
You're asking the wrong guy.
你問錯人了啦
Whatever.
再見
Hey.
話說
I'll send you info on Toma,
我會把東間事件的資料寄給你
but me and you share the same fate.
但別忘了我跟你是在同一條船上
Even if you became normal, your sins wouldn't vanish.
就算你變回一般人
What are you afraid of, Sugitani?
你在怕什麼啊
You just don't get it.
你還是不明白
What happened to the survivor?
那個存活下來的孩子後來怎麼樣了？
Takeshi, you mean?
你是說小武嗎？
If he was turned into a psychopath…
既然他被動了心理病態者改造手術…
Unfortunately, Toma's procedure was a success.
遺憾的是，東間翠的手術成功了
His behavior's been problematic,
後來他的行為一直很有問題
so there's no doubt.
所以應該不會錯
Isn't that so, Inui?
是吧，乾？
Takeshi is Kenmochi.
小武就是劍持
The reason I got demoted.
害我被貶職的那個
Takeshi Kenmochi.
劍持武士
Damn piece of shit!
混帳！
Hey! What the fuck is up with this?!
喂！搞屁啊，這什麼爛東西！
The prosecution knew?
檢察官有針對這點偵辦嗎？
Rejected as evidence of a defective personality.
證明過去行為惡劣的證據會造成偏見 因此法院不承認效力
We'll bring him in.
保護劍持武士
Other survivors might exist.
我們不曉得還有幾個孩子生還
He'll be targeted.
但劍持遲早會成為目標
Inui!
乾！
Stand down. Stay away from Kenmochi.
這次調查你不能參與
But I know him best!
但我是最了解劍持的人
Don't blow your cool.
別那麼激動
With Kitajima's help, talk to the Tomas' accomplices.
其他人借助北島先生的力量
Be thorough.
跟監他們搜集證據
Classy place to drink.
你喝酒的地方還真老派啊
Hirose said you come here on days like this.
是廣瀨先生告訴我的
What can I get you?
歡迎光臨
Ah, oolong tea.
我要烏龍茶
One oolong tea!
一杯烏龍茶
What do you want?
找我幹嘛？
Your opinion on protecting Kenmochi.
對於保護劍持這件事，你怎麼想？
Hey.
我問你
If somebody's hunting psychopaths,
如果有人在獵殺心理病態者
why stop them?
有必要阻止他嗎？
Are you serious?
你這話是認真的嗎？
Never mind that, what about Ninomiya?
話說回來，你打算拿二宮怎麼辦？
I'm sure he has psychopathic tendencies.
二宮有心理病態傾向，這點無庸置疑
He's narcissistic, and constantly unshakeable.
他很自戀，任何狀況都能坦然面對
Lies fluently to get what he wants.
為達目的，說謊也不會臉紅
Sometimes arrogant and pompous.
在某些情況下則顯得傲慢自大
Sounds more like you.
什麼啊，你在說自己嗎？
I'm not a psychopath.
請別把我跟心理病態者相提並論
Here you go.
請用，久等了
Thanks.
謝謝
So?
所以呢？
If we keep our eyes on Ninomiya, the killer will turn up,
只要緊盯著二宮
now that attacking Kenmochi is too risky.
因為犯人現在已經無法對劍持出手了
I doubt Kenmochi wants our protection.
我懷疑劍持會願意接受警察的保護
Huh?
什麼？
Scum like him will never change.
那種傢伙到死都不會變的
I'm joining you.
我也要見劍持
-Huh? -No, that's…
-什麼？ -不，這…
Listen…
聽…聽我說…
Who are you assholes?
你們誰啊？
Mr. Kenmochi.
-劍持先生 -怎樣？
May we talk with you?
方便聊一下嗎？
What for?
聊什麼？
It's possible you're in danger.
劍持先生很有可能被鎖定為攻擊目標
We'll protect you.
我們是來保護你的
Bullshit.
鬼扯
You want to keep tabs on me,
你們一定是來監視我
to pin Saki's death on me, am I right?
想要找出關於咲死亡的證據吧？
That's the kind of shit you'd pull.
很像你們會幹的爛事
If anybody wants me dead,
要說有誰想殺我
it's… that detective, Inui.
應該就是那個…姓乾的刑警吧
Nobody's more suspicious.
那傢伙是最可疑的
Mr. Kenmochi.
劍持先生
Did you know your brain has a neuro chip?
你知道自己被植入了腦內晶片嗎？
So what?
那又怎樣？
Doc said removing it was too risky,
醫生說他們不知道摘除會有什麼後果
so I left it in.
所以我就讓它留在腦子裡了
Other survivors?
還有其他生還者嗎？
Like I'd know.
我哪知道
Get this.
聽好了
Stay the hell away from me.
絕對不准跟監我
If that "brain thief" shows up, I'll rip their head off.
要是那個偷腦賊出現的話
It'd be self-defense.
這算是正當防衛
No need to make it look accidental.
連假裝成意外都不用
What does that mean?
“假裝成意外”是什麼意思？
It's a joke.
開玩笑的
There you go again.
看吧
You still think I killed her.
你們還在懷疑我
Right?
對吧？
Go on, get out of here.
搞什麼，快滾吧
Piss off, dickwads.
我叫你們快點滾啊，混帳東西
Move your asses.
喂，閃邊去
Go fuck yourselves.
搞屁啊你們
Mr. Kenmochi!
劍持先生
Hello?
喂？
What?!
什麼？
Don't do this…
別這樣
Don't do this!
住手！
Akira?
彰先生？
Why are you here?
你怎麼會來？
Your father…
荷見律師的身影…
I just can't forget.
一直在我腦海揮之不去
I…
我想…
guess I had you all wrong.
我果然是誤會你了
When he introduced you to me,
父親向我介紹你的時候
something didn't feel right.
我並不喜歡你
It seemed you were always acting.
在我看來，你總是像在演戲
Even after my father died,
父親死後也一樣
I thought you only cared about taking over.
我以為你一心只想著要繼承事務所
But now I know…
但現在我明白
you're truly mourning for him.
你是真心為父親的死感到哀痛
Thank you.
謝謝
That's Kaneki, an accomplice of the Tomas.
死者叫金木，是當時東間夫婦的共犯
He kept silent in court,
他在法庭上保持緘默
so his sentence for abetting was heavy.
因幫助他人犯罪而被處以重刑
He's been dead for more than three months.
金木死亡已經過了三個月以上
Look.
你看這邊
The brain thief must've stolen his victims list,
偷腦賊一定是 先偷走了收在這裡的被害人名單
and is using it to kill.
才去執行犯罪的吧
There goes our last lead on the killer…
這下子我們失去了偷腦賊的最後線索
I might have another.
關於這一點，我有事要稟告
Ninomiya has a neuro chip too.
二宮也被植入了腦內晶片
How did you find out? Explain yourself.
你怎麼知道的？戶城，解釋清楚
I saw his hospital records.
我看了他在醫院的病歷
You what?!
你…
Without a warrant?! He's a lawyer!
你又沒有令狀，對方可是律師耶
His attending neurosurgeon's disappeared.
為二宮診療的腦外科醫生失蹤了
The victims, Kenmochi,
如同其他被害人和劍持
and Ninomiya could be connected.
二宮也可能涉及某種犯罪
Trace his movements.
請下令跟監二宮
Proof of involvement in the disappearance?
腦外科醫生失蹤 與二宮有關的根據是什麼？
-None yet. -Connected to what crime?
-目前還沒有 -涉及某種犯罪，具體而言是什麼？
-Possibly… -Was Ninomiya last to get a chip?
-恐怕是… -他是最後僅存有植入晶片的人嗎？
I don't know.
我不確定
Toshiro.
戶城小姐
Illegal viewing of records is a matter for Internal Affairs.
你這次未獲令狀偷看病歷
Stand down.
-我要你立刻退出本案調查 -可是…
I accept that Ninomiya is important to the case.
我承認二宮律師 握有這一連串事件的重要線索
Whether we track him or not is up to the chief.
至於要不要跟監他
Hey.
那個
Are you sure I should join you?
我這樣跟來真的好嗎？
You said you wanted to.
不是你自己說想來的嗎？
Sure, but…
是沒錯啦
Akira?!
小彰？
It's been so long!
好久不見了
Your first visit since you graduated.
這是小彰你畢業後第一次回來呢
I heard you're doing well as a lawyer.
我有聽說你現在是位成功的律師喔
You've worked so hard.
你一定很努力打拚吧
You used to be such a big bully.
小時候明明是個像胖虎那樣的惡霸
Akira was a bully?
彰先生小時候像胖虎？
He was.
對啊
He always sang the same song.
他總是唱著同一首歌
How did it go?
怎麼唱來著？
Please don't dredge up the past.
拜託，這麼久以前的事別再提了
So?
所以呢？ 突然跑來是要通知結婚喜訊嗎？
Ms. Ryoko…
良子老師
Do you mind?
介意讓我們獨處嗎？
Er, may I take a look around?
請問，我可以進去參觀嗎？
Please do. The children will love it.
歡迎，孩子們也會很高興的
Was I dumped
把我丟在這裡的是這對夫婦嗎？
As I told you before,
之前我不是說過嗎？
you were four when you were left here.
你是四歲的時候被丟在育幼院門口
No one saw it.
沒有人看到是誰拋下你的
We sometimes received anonymous phone calls though.
但我們偶爾會接到匿名電話 詢問你的狀況
About what?
對方問了些什麼？
They asked rather strange questions.
問的內容啊
"Is he a smooth talker?"
對方問你是不是口齒伶俐
"Is he full of himself?"
自尊心高
"Is he not bothered by bullying?"
或是被霸凌時還能保持冷靜
Then the calls suddenly stopped.
後來突然就沒再接到這些電話了
As if they were describing me.
全部都很符合對我的形容呢
So true.
對啊
I wonder why?
究竟是什麼用意呢？
A PCL-R psychopathy test.
海爾病態人格檢核表
It's like…
總之
a personality assessment.
就是一種類似性格測驗的東西
Is that right?
這樣啊
You really are a lawyer now.
真不愧是律師呢
You know everything.
什麼都懂
You're a lot softer and kinder.
你圓融許多，變得很溫柔
Must be thanks to her.
想必是受她的影響吧
Thank you.
今天非常感謝
Take care.
那就再見囉
See you.
再見
Let the sunshine in
太陽公公放光芒
Let it shine on the little rock
照耀在小石頭上
Let the heat of the sunlight
用溫暖的陽光
Warm up the rock plenty
滿滿照耀地上
When I was sitting down Next to the little rock
當我坐在，小石頭旁
Funny thing is I became a little rock too
彷彿變得，也像石頭一樣
And my heart got warm inside bit by bit
心中漸漸，溫暖清朗
It made me so happy That I wanted to sing out loud
使我開心，想要歌唱
Let the sunshine in
太陽公公放光芒
Let it shine on me too
也照耀在我身上
Let the heat of the sunlight
用溫暖的陽光
Warm me up plenty
滿滿照耀地上
Let the sunshine in
太陽公公放光芒
Let it shine on me too
也照耀在我身上
Let the heat of the sunlight
用溫暖的陽光
Warm me up plenty
滿滿照耀地上
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Nothing…
沒事
It's your first time coming back.
一定是因為你太久沒回來這裡了
Munch, munch, gulp.
“嚼…吞下
The monstrous lumberjack ate Hans.
怪物樵夫吃掉了漢斯
When its stomach became full,
吃飽了的怪物樵夫
it finally realized.
終於發現了一件事
"Wait…"
‘等等
"What Hans said is true."
話說回來，漢斯說的沒錯
"I spend more time as a lumberjack than a monster."
比起身為怪物
"Am I not a monster,
或許我不是怪物
but just a mere lumberjack?"
而只是個樵夫？’
"The monstrous lumberjack
怪物樵夫
suddenly became confused about its true identity."
突然搞不清楚自己到底是誰了”
So that's it…
原來如此
I know who it is…
那傢伙的真面目是…
What is this, Sugitani?
你想幹嘛，杉谷？
Why pretend to be the monster?
為什麼要偽裝成怪物樵夫？
You really can't kill now.
現在的你果然狠不下心殺人
I knew it, but it's a letdown.
我早這麼覺得了，但還是很失望
Did you think I'd sell you out?
你以為我會這麼多嘴 把你的事說出去嗎？
Don't worry.
別擔心
I know who the monster is.
我已經知道那傢伙的真面目了
I'll have my data soon.
我馬上就會拿到資料
So, we're still a team?
所以
Yeah.
是啊
Prepare for the surgery.
準備動手術吧
What a relief.
太好了
If you really mean that…
如果你真有這個打算…
Of course, you becoming normal
當然，你如果變回一般人
would've been a fun experiment.
也會是一項非常有趣的實驗
Pathetic morality probably would've been your downfall.
只不過，你一定會被庸俗的良心 害得自取滅亡
Everything alright?
有什麼事嗎？
Ms. Ranko Toshiro, correct?
你的名字是戶城嵐子吧？
You have a PhD from MIT.
都讀到麻省理工學院的博士了
Why be a poorly paid cop?
為什麼跑去當低薪的警官？
You looked me up.
你調查過我的事了嗎？
Over 20 years ago,
20多年前
a man entered an elementary school,
有個男人闖進一間小學
and slaughtered nine young children.
殺害了九名孩童
All just to…
凶手只是…
receive a death sentence.
為了能讓自己獲判死刑
My older brother
我哥哥
was one of that selfish man's victims.
也死在了那個自私男的手下
I see.
原來如此
You want revenge in a roundabout way?
你現在算是在進行間接的復仇嗎？
A psychopath would see it like that.
在心理病態者眼中看來是這樣的吧
What are you insinuating?
這句話是什麼意思呢？
Mr. Ninomiya.
二宮先生
There's a neuro chip in your head?
你的頭部被植入了腦內晶片吧？
Aha.
我明白了
You checked my records without a warrant?
你沒有取得令狀，卻偷看了我的病歷
To get to the truth, I stop at nothing.
為了調查真相，我願意不擇手段
Whatever's in my brain,
不論我的腦子裡被裝了什麼
it might make me more sane than you.
或許正因此，使我比你還像個人
Being a psychopath isn't a crime.
身為心理病態者並沒有罪
Don't judge a person on their personality.
該被制裁的不是人格
Judge their actions.
而是行為
Why…
你…
did you come alone?
為什麼獨自跑來找我？
Because…
那是因為…
Your illegal search got you dismissed.
我違法調查，被調查小組除名了
So,
這代表
whatever happens to you here,
你在這裡不論發生什麼事
no one will know.
都不會有人知道
I won't take your bait.
我是不會上鉤的
I'm sure you're recording audio or video of me.
我猜，你一定有錄音或錄影吧
-Hello? -Did you say anything to Inui?
喂？
Inui?
乾先生？
Why, sir?
為什麼問這個？
Kenmochi got away.
劍持不見了
He's gone missing.
他趁跟監員警不注意的瞬間溜走了
Listen.
什麼？
Did you get Inui to
因為自己被迫退出調查
Hey.
我問你
If somebody's hunting psychopaths,
如果有人在獵殺心理病態者
why stop them?
有必要阻止他嗎？
Are you serious?
你這話是認真的嗎？
That detective, Inui.
那個姓乾的刑警
Nobody's more suspicious.
那傢伙是最可疑的
Scum like him will never change.
那種傢伙到死都不會變的
For caution's sake,
為了慎重起見，我問你
does Inui fit your profile?
乾有符合你心目中的罪犯側寫嗎？
Give me his address.
請告訴我乾先生住在哪裡
FROM: EMI HASUMI
（寄件人：荷見映美）
COME TO THE TOMAS' MANSION
（到東間家的宅邸來）
Now the monstrous lumberjack
“這下子怪物樵夫
had no friends left that it could talk to.
再也沒有能聽他說話的朋友了
"What should I do?"
‘怎麼辦…’
Upset, the monstrous lumberjack
不知如何是好的怪物樵夫
decided to go and make new friends
為了結交新的朋友
in another village.
而去了另一個村莊
Upon arriving in the new village,
來到新村莊的怪物樵夫
it snuck into the house of the local lumberjack.
躲進了那個村子裡的樵夫家
Then,
接著，他把那個家中的嬰兒 耳朵壓平拉大
and used a stone to sharpen its teeth into fangs.
用石頭把嬰兒的牙齒磨尖
"Now this child is a monstrous lumberjack too."
‘這麼一來 這孩子也變成怪物樵夫了’”
Akira, run!
彰，快逃！
Run!
快逃！
Inui?
乾先生？
Inui?!
乾先生
And so, the monstrous lumberjack
“怪物樵夫用同樣的手法
visited many new villages, and made many new friends.
去了許多村莊
It hoped that one day, its friends would teach it
他相信總有一天，等朋友們長大
whether it is a monster,
就能告訴他，他到底是怪物還是樵夫
The monstrous lumberjack made many new friends.
於是怪物樵夫
Inui?
乾先生？
Whoa, what's all this?
喂…搞什麼啊？
Inui…
乾先生
You didn't have to bust my door.
你們別弄壞別人家的門好嗎？
You thought I was the killer?
你們該不會以為我是凶手吧？
What a joke. Don't waste your time.
太荒謬了吧，拜託別鬧了
Why not answer our calls?
你為什麼不接手機？
This isn't my case anymore, so get off my back.
我已經不負責這個案子了
Whose grave?
掃墓？
Saki Kenmochi.
劍持咲的墓
Died two years ago today.
今天是她過世兩週年的忌日
Oddly enough, pretty flowers had been laid there.
奇怪的是
Her relatives are all gone.
明明她的親人都已經不在了
You lose.
你輸了
Then…
既然如此
why not take off that stupid mask?
何不脫下你那可笑的面具？
After all,
反正
I know who you are.
我已經知道你的真面目了
Behavior modification…
行為改變
Damn, I should've known!
真不甘心，原來是這麼回事
Where…?!
你要去哪裡？
How did you know?
你怎麼知道的？
I know…
你一定是…
that for some reason,
因為某個緣故
your neuro chip broke.
導致腦內晶片損壞了吧？
You can empathize again.
恢復同理心的你
You can feel guilt for what you've done.
對自己做過的事懷抱罪惡感
So you started hunting psychopaths.
於是開始獵殺心理病態者
Hey! Toshiro!
喂，戶城！
Can't let them kill each other.
不能讓他們兩人互相殘殺
Two years ago,
兩年前
that Rottweiler cop hit me,
被那個煩人的刑警揍過之後
I've been changing, little by little.
我漸漸有了改變
I'd only lived for self-gratification and rage, then,
原本我過著 只感受得到快樂和憤怒的人生
out of the blue…
突然之間
different emotions rose up.
出現了新的情感
Pain and shock.
痛苦和驚訝
Joy and sadness.
愉悅和傷心
I could feel what other people felt…
能夠同理他人感受的我
and something welled up inside me.
湧出了一股無以名狀的心情
I came to my senses.
我終於明白
I found a reason to live outside of myself.
活著的意義並不只是為了自我滿足
But that…
但是，這個體悟
brought despair as well.
卻也使我感到絕望
I once had a wife who trusted me.
像我這種人，妻子還願意相信我
She was all I had.
她是我最重要的人
I killed her with my bare hands.
我卻親手殺了她
If so…
既然如此
please let this woman go.
那就放了她吧
There's…
反正我已經
nothing I can do now.
只能任你擺布了
Akira!
彰先生！
At first,
一開始
I wanted to reform you manmade psychopaths.
我想跟你們這些 被變成心理病態者的人講道理
But,
然而
as I investigated your kind,
調查之後
I found out that
我發現你們每個傢伙
many people around you died, with no consequences.
身邊都有許多人莫名死去
That woman's father was one of them.
包括她的父親，對吧？
I'm sure…
一定是你
you shoved him off that building.
把他從大樓推下去的吧？
He's lying, right?
這不是真的吧
Akira?
彰先生？
Erasing your kind from existence
把你們這些傢伙解決掉
is the only way I can repay Saki.
是我唯一能回報咲的方法
From now on,
我不會…
I won't let your kind kill again.
再讓你們殺害任何人了
Please don't!
住手！
So that's it…
我就知道
So that's why
果然是這樣
you let that witness go who saw you at the parking lot.
你在停車場攻擊我的時候
I know why.
原來你…
You can only kill us psychopaths.
只下得了手殺我們這些心理病態者啊
Now,
那麼
this woman's not your hostage.
這個女的不再是你的人質
She's mine.
而是我的了
Akira…?
彰先生？
Damn you…
你這傢伙
I was going to play along, but no more.
我原本想陪你演完這鬧劇，但是算了
Give me the data, or else
把資料交出來
I'll kill this woman.
我就殺了這個女的
Don't do it.
住手
It's true.
沒錯
I killed your father.
是我殺了你父親
And you're next.
被自己心愛的人…
Killed by the man you love. How romantic.
親手殺死，不是很浪漫嗎？
Akira!
彰先生
Please, don't do this!
拜託你住手！
Don't do it.
住手
Don't do it, dammit!
我叫你住手！
The one you wanted to kill most
你最想殺死的
is yourself.
是自己吧？
How did you guess?
你怎麼會知道？
Just like you,
我跟你一樣
in that moment,
那個時候…
my neuro chip must've broken too.
我的腦內晶片似乎也壞了
You mean, you're…
也就是說，你其實…
The data's in here?
資料存在這裡面嗎？
Photos of it.
我拍了照片
Of our families before our abductions too.
還有我們被誘拐前的家庭狀況
Yours was also…
你也一樣
a family free of violence and crime,
原本是在一個遠離暴力和犯罪的家庭
who raised you lovingly.
在父母的關愛中成長
You were a crybaby,
雖然是個愛哭鬼
but you watched out for kids smaller than you.
卻常常照顧比自己小的孩子
Even after being brought here,
被帶來這裡之後
you cried at the thought of your dad and mom worrying.
一想到爸媽會擔心，你還是會哭泣
How will you use the data?
你打算拿資料來做什麼？
For surgery,
拿來動手術
to make you a monster again?
把自己變回怪物嗎？
I…
我…
owe her…
都是托她的福
for teaching me not all emotions are a burden.
才明白人的情感並不全都是負擔
So…
所以
No surgery for me.
我不會動手術
Really…
這樣啊
That means, just now…
原來剛剛…
you had me totally fooled.
我徹底被你騙得團團轉
But I…
但是我…
can't live with this pain anymore.
已經無法再承受這種痛苦了
Can you?
你承受得了嗎？
Pain, as in guilt?
心中的罪惡感嗎？
I find that intriguing.
我很想知道…
Living with guilt, as you described.
你所謂的“活著”是什麼 包含這一點在內
Really…
這樣啊
Not just that.
除此之外
Now I'm human, I'm invincible.
擁有人心之後的我是最強的
To find the meaning of life,
為了明白活著的意義
I'll…
我會…
outlive you all.
堅決活下去
That's where we differ…
你跟我真的很不同呢
Akira.
彰
Leave him alone!
住手
Get off me, Takeshi!
快放手，小武
Akira, run!
彰，快逃！
Run!
快逃！
-Stop! Takeshi! No! -Akira!
好了，小武
Takeshi…?
你是小武？
You remember, huh?
你想起來了嗎？
I couldn't save you…
當時我救不了你
Forgive me.
對不起
Good luck with being human…
希望你能成為一個普通人
Akira.
彰
Kenmochi!
劍持！
Toshiro! Stay back!
戶城，不能過去
Kenmochi! Don't die!
劍持，你不准死！
You can't just go in!
你不能這樣擅自跑進來
I'm sorry, she barged in…
很抱歉，這位小姐硬闖進來
It's fine.
沒關係
Ms. Toshiro. What is it now?
戶城小姐，有什麼事嗎？
Why did you make me go there?
你為什麼要把我引到那個地方？
You knew about the tracker.
你知道我裝了衛星定位器吧？
It was discarded at the mansion.
定位器被丟在東間的宅邸裡
Why…
你呢？
do you think?
你是怎麼想的？
In case you couldn't defeat the monster.
為了以防 自己無法打倒那個戴面具的怪物
You used me.
你利用了我
We're confirming the brain thief was Kenmochi.
我們正在盡快證明劍持就是偷腦賊
He killed other manmade psychopaths
他殺害其他被改造成心理病態者的人
as penance for his sins.
是為了贖罪
And you killed him before he killed you.
而你則在被劍持幹掉之前 反過來殺了他
Mr. Ninomiya.
二宮先生
You're a victim of the Tomas too.
你也是東間事件的受害者
You'll live with a sin that wasn't your own?
你打算背負著 不屬於自己的罪過活下去嗎？
Ms. Toshiro.
戶城小姐
No one can escape from themselves.
沒有人能夠逃離自己
I won't make excuses for the way I live.
我不打算帶著藉口活下去
Excuse me, I should take this.
抱歉
Mr. Ninomiya.
二宮先生
I'm going to take you down.
我一定會逮捕你的
Till then, don't die on me.
所以在那之前，你千萬別死
What does he mean, no surgery?
他說不動手術了，搞什麼
Akira's such a liar.
彰這個大騙子
You're awake.
你醒來啦？
Better take it easy.
不要勉強自己喔
Akira…
彰先生
I…
我…
It's all over.
一切都結束了
I'll explain what happened.
昨天的事，我會好好解釋
I scared you.
讓你受驚嚇了
Forgive me.
對不起
Not just for my father…
這不只是為父親報仇
You only ever wanted to use me!
你果然是想要利用我而已
You didn't care how I felt at all!
狠狠踐踏了我的心意
I won't forgive you! How could I ever?!
不可原諒，我怎麼可能原諒你
Now it's self-defense.
這樣你就算是正當防衛了
Go…
聽我說
to that female cop.
快去找那個女刑警
Akira?
彰先生
I…
我…
Just go.
別說了，快去吧
Go!
快去！
The monstrous lumberjack…
於是怪物樵夫…
made many…
做了…
new friends…
好多好多的朋友
BASED ON THE NOVEL KAIBUTSU NO KIKORI BY MAYUSUKE KURAI
（改編自倉井眉介同名原著小說）